{
  "title": "Obstetrics",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "A woman who is rhesus negative undergoes amniocentesis at 16 weeks. What dose of anti D immunoglobulin should she receive immediately after the procedure?",
      "options": [
        "250 IU",
        "500IU",
        "1000IU",
        "1500IU",
        "2000IU"
      ],
      "answer": "250 IU"
    },
    {
      "question": "You have just examined a 28-year-old primigravida in spontaneous labour. Examination findings are 0/5 palpable per abdomen, cervix is 7 cm dilated, cephalic presentation, -1 station, anterior fontanelle palpable with orbital ridges and nasal bridge felt anteriorly. What is the presenting diameter of the fetus?",
      "options": [
        "Mentovertical",
        "Occipitofrontal",
        "Submentobregmatic",
        "Suboccipitobregmatic",
        "Suboccipitofrontal"
      ],
      "answer": "Mentovertical"
    },
    {
      "question": "A 21-year-old woman, who is known to have beta thalassemia major, attends the clinic for preconception counselling. What is the most relevant initial pre-pregnancy investigation to predict maternal complications of pregnancy?",
      "options": [
        "Cardiac MRI",
        "Chest X-Ray",
        "ECG",
        "Echocardiogram",
        "Pulmonary function tests"
      ],
      "answer": "Echocardiogram"
    },
    {
      "question": "A 34-year-old woman attends for her booking in her third pregnancy. She had a caesarean section in her first pregnancy 4 years ago and has had a successful vaginal birth after caesarean section (VBAC) 2 years ago. She has a BMI OF 26. What is the best predictor for a successful VBAC?",
      "options": [
        "BMI of less than 30",
        "Less than 35 years old",
        "Previous vaginal birth",
        "Short inter-pregnancy interval",
        "Spontaneous onset of labour"
      ],
      "answer": "Previous vaginal birth"
    },
    {
      "question": "You are asked to see a 21-year-old woman for preconceptual care. She was diagnosed with generalised tonic-clonic epilepsy four years ago. This is poorly controlled. She is currently on sodium valproate and levetiracetam. What is the next step in her management?",
      "options": [
        "Arrange MRI",
        "Arrange an EEG",
        "Commence aspirin 75 mg",
        "Commence folic acid 5 mg",
        "Review medication"
      ],
      "answer": "Review medication"
    },
    {
      "question": "A 28-year-old woman attends the mental health antenatal clinic at 12 weeks for a booking assessment. This is her first baby. Which condition gives her the highest risk of puerperal psychosis?",
      "options": [
        "Anorexia nervosa",
        "Bipolar affective disorder",
        "Moderate depression",
        "Obsessive compulsive disorder",
        "Recurrent anxiety"
      ],
      "answer": "Bipolar affective disorder"
    },
    {
      "question": "A woman has had a recent uncomplicated vaginal delivery but has developed a significant post-partum pyrexia and tachycardia. She is thought to be allergic to penicillin. You suspect puerperal sepsis and are keen to commence treatment prior to the investigations coming back. What is the antibiotic regime of choice?",
      "options": [
        "Cefuroxime",
        "Clindamycin",
        "Co-amoxiclav",
        "Erythromycin",
        "Metronidazole"
      ],
      "answer": "Cefuroxime"
    },
    {
      "question": "In order to help plan the capacity required for providing future maternity services you are asked to design a study to establish the incidence of vaginal birth following previous caesarean section. The study will require establishing the mode of delivery in women who have either had only vaginal delivery or have had a caesarean section in at least one previous pregnancy. You review the epidemiological study methods that may be appropriate for this type of study. Which type of research study should you choose?",
      "options": [
        "Case control",
        "Cohort",
        "Cross sectional",
        "Ecological",
        "Survey"
      ],
      "answer": "Cohort"
    },
    {
      "question": "A woman has an instrumental delivery of a baby weighing 3950 g in her first pregnancy. A Grade 3C tear of the anal sphincter is identified. An appropriate overlapping repair using 3/0 PDS is performed. Prior to discharge, she asks about the long-term risk of faecal or flatal incontinence. What percentage risk would you advise?",
      "options": [
        "10%",
        "20%",
        "30%",
        "40%",
        "50%"
      ],
      "answer": "40%"
    },
    {
      "question": "A couple, both aged 32, wish to start a family. They have stopped using contraception and are having regular sexual intercourse. How likely are they to conceive within one year?",
      "options": [
        "70-74%",
        "75-79%",
        "80-84%",
        "85-89%",
        "90-94%"
      ],
      "answer": "85-89%"
    }
  ]
}